<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelance Web Developer</title>
    <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Freelance Web Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:23:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.kristasimmons.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopify Theme Development Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/shopify-dev-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 12:23:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/shopify-dev-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple step-by-step workflow to set up a Shopify Development Environment from the command line. The idea is to keep a similar workflow to other dev environments. A similar workflow would mean managing the theme files locally by making changes and committing those changes with Git while running a command line tool to watch for changes and automatically update the theme on the Shopify store.
This post is a brief primer on setting up your Shopify dev environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Craftsmanship</title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/software-craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 12:13:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/software-craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>In a recent interview I was asked to define what &amp;ldquo;software craftsmanship&amp;rdquo; means to me. I felt a sense of relief answering this question. Not only because it was a change of pace from a technical whiteboard question, but I had recently reflected on the similarities between software development and another passion of mine. From my understanding, having craftsmanship is the pursuit of furthering your knowledge and skills towards an activity or passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 minute rule</title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/20-minute-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 12:02:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/20-minute-rule/</guid>
      <description>For any new programmers who are starting off at their junior developer position or internship, I have some advice: The 20 Minute Rule (when to ask for help).
When I first started my web development internship at scientist.com, it was a bit overwhelming. Jumping into a massive codebase and making sure you don’t set anything on fire or bring down the company’s online platform had literally given me nightmares. Once I got over that hump, I ran into a new issue I hadn’t faced before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running my site with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/hugo-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 12:23:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/blog/hugo-blog/</guid>
      <description>Now wishing I would&amp;rsquo;ve started my web dev/designer blog a long time ago! I have a Wordpress music blog, but I wanted to try a new form of blogging for this one.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently launching a separate site specifically for my blog, but in the meantime I will start posting content here on my portfolio site. The blog is being created using Hugo, which is a static site generator and it&amp;rsquo;s being hosted through github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-1/</guid>
      <description>VolunteerUP is an app that connects nonprofit organizations with eager volunteers. Users are able to register as volunteers, search for events in their area, and sign up for events as volunteers. Users are also able to register as organizers that administer their nonprofit organization pages, create a calendar of events, and request volunteers. Check out the project on Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-2/</guid>
      <description>Helped build out Organik SEO&amp;rsquo;s new website. Involved in building out custom post type </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-5/</guid>
      <description>A modern home &amp;amp; sign up design for an iOS App. Created the design based on the web app VolunteerUP, which I previously helped co-develop during my time at LEARN Academy. I wanted to stay consistent with the original app, so I stuck to the same font and color scheme. This is my first iOS app design and surley won&amp;rsquo;t be my last! I used draw.io to create a user flowchart prior to the low-fidelity prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-6/</guid>
      <description>Weather Watcher is a weather app that will take in a location and produce the degrees in F, the location, weather icon, percentage humidity, windspeed and direction. Depending on the weather (ex. sunny, raining, snow, etc.) a different icon will show each time.
I utilized the OpenWeatherMap Api and added in the ability to have the weather updated by current geographic location rather than inputing a zip code or city. If a user&amp;rsquo;s browser isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by geolocation, then it will prompt the user to manually enter in their zip code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-7/</guid>
      <description>This Hi-Lo Game was created with jQuery and Javascript. A user is given 7 tries to guess the computer generated number from 1-100. Each time the player clicks the &amp;ldquo;Submit Guess&amp;rdquo; button, it will print out the number of tries left at the bottom of the game screen page. View code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>