<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Works on Freelance Web Developer</title>
    <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Works on Freelance Web Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-1/</guid>
      <description>VolunteerUP is an app that connects nonprofit organizations with eager volunteers. Users are able to register as volunteers, search for events in their area, and sign up for events as volunteers. Users are also able to register as organizers that administer their nonprofit organization pages, create a calendar of events, and request volunteers. Check out the project on Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-10/</guid>
      <description>Built with CSS Grid. A dream board (or vision board) is a visual tool that serves as a visual representation of your dreams and your ideal life View demo site View code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-11/</guid>
      <description>Built a custom Shopify store for a consumer packaged goods client. Used the liquid templating language, jQuery, HTML, CSS. Fully responsive site with custom built features such as the homepage product slider. View dev site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-12/</guid>
      <description>Agency73 was looking for a branding revamp in order to improve their online presence and upcoming marketing efforts. I redid their whole website, as well as designing marketing materials to send to prospective clients. Their old existing website didn’t clearly communicate their service offering and lacked a personal/appealing look and feel. There weren’t any style guides or design mockups to refer to, so I had the opportunity to drive both the design and development efforts for this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-13/</guid>
      <description>I was tasked to build out a landing page for Honma Golf&amp;rsquo;s marketing efforts. Honma recently re-developed their US eCommerce website and decided to build it on Shopify. They needed a quick solution for their sales reps to send out an email blast to current and prospective clients about their new clubs. Because of the design complexities and number of products they wanted to showcase, we decided to build a landing page template in Shopify vs an HTML email template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-14/</guid>
      <description>Helped build out Organik SEO&amp;rsquo;s new website. Involved in building out custom post type </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-2/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to build out the UI for a marketing anomaly detection project at Agency73. I had previously expressed interest in bettering my skills in a JavaScript framework, and fortunate enough, Agency73 wanted me to code out this project’s UI. We decided to use Vue.JS as the front-end framework.
Without getting into too much into detail, the primary objective of this project was to create a proof of concept machine learning-based tool that would:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-5/</guid>
      <description>A modern home &amp;amp; sign up design for an iOS App. Created the design based on the web app VolunteerUP, which I previously helped co-develop during my time at LEARN Academy. I wanted to stay consistent with the original app, so I stuck to the same font and color scheme. This is my first iOS app design and surley won&amp;rsquo;t be my last! I used draw.io to create a user flowchart prior to the low-fidelity prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-6/</guid>
      <description>Weather Watcher is a weather app that will take in a location and produce the degrees in F, the location, weather icon, percentage humidity, windspeed and direction. Depending on the weather (ex. sunny, raining, snow, etc.) a different icon will show each time.
I utilized the OpenWeatherMap Api and added in the ability to have the weather updated by current geographic location rather than inputing a zip code or city. If a user&amp;rsquo;s browser isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by geolocation, then it will prompt the user to manually enter in their zip code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-7/</guid>
      <description>This Hi-Lo Game was created with jQuery and Javascript. A user is given 7 tries to guess the computer generated number from 1-100. Each time the player clicks the &amp;ldquo;Submit Guess&amp;rdquo; button, it will print out the number of tries left at the bottom of the game screen page. View code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-8/</guid>
      <description>Here I built out a responsive landing page using a sass/gulp workflow. I decided to develop a travel landing page for my hometown, Ventura California. View demo site View code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kristasimmons.io/work/proj-9/</guid>
      <description>Developed an agency landing page template for Design Revision. Utilized Bootstrap for with a mobile-first approach. View demo site View code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>